<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welsh Technical Standards Board</title>
    <link>https://standards.cymru/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Welsh Technical Standards Board</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 09:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://standards.cymru/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-12-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-12-17/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-11-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-11-26/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-10-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-10-29/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-09-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-09-24/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-08-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-08-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-06-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-06-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-07-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-07-23/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focusing on developers</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-05-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-05-30/</guid>
      <description> Review of minutes from March meeting and sign-off to publish on website. Review of action log. Review of website and its backend technology including github.com code and potential (Mark Wardle) Presentation on existing development practices in Wales (Rob Jones / Huw Angle on behalf of Geoff Norton, NWIS software development manager) Review of current ecosystem developer view and presentation from Paul Howells/Helen Northmore on DHEW/ecosystem.  Invited:
 WTSB members Helen Northmore Catrin Rees Paul Howells Huw Angle selected health board developers (tbc)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using standards to change culture</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/posts/2019-04-24-standards-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 04:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/posts/2019-04-24-standards-culture/</guid>
      <description>Our mission is to :
 support the creation and maintenance of a catalogue of standards and requirements to enable integration and interoperability across all health and care systems in a consistent and secure manner, and to support local innovation and the use of third party delivery partners.
from WTSB Terms of Reference
 And we are working hard to build that catalogue.
But is that all we need to do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual meeting to draft letter following statement of principles</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-04-18/index./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-04-18/index./</guid>
      <description> Agenda  Discussion of draft letter call-for-action after statement of principles have been endorsed by National Informatics Management Board (NIMB) - See shared document (standards board members only)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic prescribing standards and statement of principles sign-off</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-03-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-03-28/</guid>
      <description> Agenda  Minutes and Actions from February meeting - see link or Document 1 in bundle Presentation from e-prescribing team Discussion ahead of National Informatics Management Board (NIMB) – 11 April NIMB consideration of Statements of Principles - Doc 2 Any other business  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling medications</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/posts/2019-03-28-medications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 12:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/posts/2019-03-28-medications/</guid>
      <description>“When we set out to write software, we never know enough. Knowledge on the project is fragmented, scattered among many people and documents, and it’s mixed with other information so that we don’t even know which bits of knowledge we really need. Domains that seem less technically daunting can be deceiving: we don’t realize how much we don’t know. This ignorance leads us to make false assumptions.”
Excerpt From: Eric Evans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statement of intent, community integration and work plans</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-02-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2019-02-26/</guid>
      <description> Agenda  Final discussions and sign off of statement of intent Discussion of community and social care integration and interoperability standards Consideration of new document detailing resources and requirements for work packages Review of website / blog and API documentation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of reference</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 21:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/about/</guid>
      <description>Purpose The purpose of the Welsh Technical Standards Board (WTSB) is to support the creation and maintenance of a catalogue of standards and requirements to enable integration and interoperability across all health and care systems in a consistent and secure manner, and to support local innovation and the use of third party delivery partners.
The scope of this Board covers:
 Interoperability Standards Integration standards Software development standards Infrastructure standards Cyber security standards  Responsibilities: The WTSB is responsible for the following (in line with its agreed scope):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A statement of principles</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-12-01-wtsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 22:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-12-01-wtsb/</guid>
      <description>On the 18th December, the Welsh Technical Standards Board discussed how we might draft some broad principles and a statement of intent, setting out our broad approach, our ethos, our principles and how we were going to tackle the work we need to do, so that, in effect, we set the standards to enable us to build a truly open platform for health and care in Wales.
After lots of discussion and debate, we submitted our work to Wales&amp;rsquo; National Informatics Management Boards and they were endorsed in a meeting on 11th April 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronic observations</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-11-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-11-21/</guid>
      <description> Minutes and Actions - Doc 1 Summary of e-Observations work and INTERopen FHIR profiling Review of the Standards Process: https://wardle.org/wales/2018/10/07/wtsb.html ADT standards Interoperability framework Doc 2 Outline for standards catalogue Doc 3 AOB   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing processes for managing standards in Wales</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-09-27-wtsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 21:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-09-27-wtsb/</guid>
      <description>Our September NHS Wales Technical Standards Board was held on the 27th September.
We have been asked to identify, assess, set and assure technical principles and standards in NHS Wales. That means we need to build a catalogue of standards, including standards that are already in use as well as standards that should be used for new developments. We must recognise a need for pragmatism, so a catalogue must include not only information about that technical standard but how it should be implemented and used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processes for standards evaluation</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-09-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-09-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standards assessments</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-08-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-08-28/</guid>
      <description> Welcome &amp;amp; introductions Action Log Technical Standard assessment - draft process &amp;amp; templates:  Process flow Request template Assessment template Outcome template  Technical Standards Catalogue – what information should it contain? Forward Workplan:  Template plan Upcoming standards  AOB  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processes in Welsh Information Standards Board</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-07-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-07-17/</guid>
      <description> Welcome &amp;amp; introductions Action Log - Doc 1 WISB information standards development process - Rebecca Cook WTSB processes and templates – discussion External Groups and WTSB Developer portal for Wales mock-up AOB   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adopting GDS principles and thinking about documentation</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-06-19-wtsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 20:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-06-19-wtsb/</guid>
      <description>We held the second meeting of the Welsh Technical Standards Board (WTSB) today and I am delighted to announce that we have formally adopted the GDS Design Principles for use by NHS Wales. These are:
 Start with user needs Do less Design with data Do the hard work to make it simple Iterate. Then iterate again This is for everyone Understand context Build digital services, not websites Be consistent, not uniform Make things open: it makes things better  In addition, we have agreed to adopt the Welsh Government Digital Service Standard:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms of reference / developers / GDS</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-06-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-06-19/</guid>
      <description>Welcome &amp;amp; introductions Action Log - Doc 1 Updated Terms of Reference for sign off - Doc 2 Discussion relating a developer/standards portal e.g. https://developer.wales.nhs.uk or https://standards.cymru Current Standards in use across NHS Wales – Rob Jones, Doc 3a,b,c Proposed standards for consideration, Doc 4a,b  GDS Design Principles GDS Service Standards e-Observations  NHS Wales System Architecture Review - Doc 5 AOB  Date of next meeting: 10:00-12:30 - 17th July</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural meeting</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-05-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/meetings/2018-05-22/</guid>
      <description> Welcome &amp;amp; introductions Terms of Reference and membership - Doc 1 How the Board will function - outputs - Doc 2 (copy of NIMB paper) Proposed technical standards for consideration
 INTEROPen and membership of other relevant groups
 AOB   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Welsh Technical Standards Board</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/posts/introducing-wtsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 20:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/posts/introducing-wtsb/</guid>
      <description>I am delighted to announce that I have been asked to chair the new Welsh Technical Standards Board (WTSB) for NHS Wales. We will support the creation and maintenance of a catalogue of standards and requirements to enable integration and interoperability across all health and care systems in a consistent and secure manner, and to support local innovation and the use of third party delivery partners.
The scope of this Board covers:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>