<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Approved on Welsh Technical Standards Board</title>
    <link>https://standards.cymru/status/approved/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Approved on Welsh Technical Standards Board</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://standards.cymru/status/approved/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Medication</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/standards/medication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/standards/medication/</guid>
      <description>At the meeting of WTSB on 28th March 2019, we agreed that structured medication data should adopt the HL7 FHIR medication standards, with profiles aligned with the medication profiles from NHS England and INTEROpen. Further information can be found in the associated blog post from this meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A statement of principles</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-12-01-wtsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 22:25:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-12-01-wtsb/</guid>
      <description>On the 18th December, the Welsh Technical Standards Board discussed how we might draft some broad principles and a statement of intent, setting out our broad approach, our ethos, our principles and how we were going to tackle the work we need to do, so that, in effect, we set the standards to enable us to build a truly open platform for health and care in Wales.
After lots of discussion and debate, we submitted our work to Wales&amp;rsquo; National Informatics Management Boards and they were endorsed in a meeting on 11th April 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adopting GDS principles and thinking about documentation</title>
      <link>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-06-19-wtsb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 20:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standards.cymru/posts/2018-06-19-wtsb/</guid>
      <description>We held the second meeting of the Welsh Technical Standards Board (WTSB) today and I am delighted to announce that we have formally adopted the GDS Design Principles for use by NHS Wales. These are:
 Start with user needs Do less Design with data Do the hard work to make it simple Iterate. Then iterate again This is for everyone Understand context Build digital services, not websites Be consistent, not uniform Make things open: it makes things better  In addition, we have agreed to adopt the Welsh Government Digital Service Standard:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>